Guide to the National Alliance on Mental Illness - Finger Lakes Records, 1985-2010.
National Alliance on Mental Illness - Finger Lakes Records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
National Alliance on Mental Illness - Finger Lakes Records, 1985-2010.
6956
National Alliance on Mental Illness - Finger Lakes
4.0 cubic feet.
Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Educational and publicity materials and files on meetings and activities of FLAMI and NAMI-Finger Lakes.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Under the name Finger Lakes Alliance on Mental Illness (FLAMI) since 1985 and National Alliance on Mental Illness (NAMI)- Finger Lakes since it incorporated as a 501c organization in 2006, this group has organized support for and education about having family members and friends with mental illness.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Educational and publicity materials and files on meetings and activities of FLAMI and NAMI-Finger Lakes, arranged basically chronologically, with audiocassettes and ephemera separate at the end.
SUBJECTS
Names:
National Alliance on Mental Illness - Finger Lakes; Finger Lakes Alliance on Mental Illness.
Subjects:
Mental illness--Finger Lakes Region (N.Y.); Mental disorders--Finger Lakes Region (N.Y.); Mental health services--Finger Lakes Region (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- What Families Need to Know: information packets 1982-undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- NAMI (National Alliance for the Mentally Ill): publications 1982-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Syracuse Transitional Living Supportive Family Training, Sheila Le Gacy 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Finger Lakes Alliance for the Mentally Ill (FLAMI): Correspondence 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Counseling Skills - Ed Franzoni, Ph.D. 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- FLAMI: Agendas 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- FLAMI: Annual Report 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- FLAMI: Clipping 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- FLAMI: Financial statements 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- AMI-NYS (Alliance for the Mentally Ill-New York State) 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Educational talks and speeches 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- FLAMI: Education Committee information 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- FLAMI: Education Conference 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- A History of the National Alliance for the Mentally Ill (NAMI) 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- FLAMI: Vocational and Job Opportunities Pilot Project 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- AMI-NYS: Membership information 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- NAMI: Membership information 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mental Illness Awareness Week 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- FLAMI: Minutes 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Madelaine Goodrich petition 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Membership lists 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- P. R. kit for Mental Illness Awareness Week 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Legislative issues 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- FLAMI: Agendas 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- AMI: Agendas, Cayuga County 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Miscellany 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- FLAMI: President correspondence 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- FLAMI: Expenses 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- FLAMI: Financial statements 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Program notices 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- FLAMI: Talks 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Ed Surell's talk on abnormal psychology 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Legislative information 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Legislative issues 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- AMI-NYS 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Supportive Family Training, Sheil Le Gacy 1989 (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- FLAMI: Financial statements 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- NAMI/FLAMI: By-laws 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- NAMI/FLAMI: Agendas 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- NAMI/FLAMI: Legislative issues 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Membership NAMI/AMI-NYS 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Richard Surles Educational program 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Planning Fmily Education meeting 1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Family home management of chronic mental illness - program outline 1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous notes, etc. 1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Principles of professional and family collaboration 1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Family Ties newsletter 1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- FLAMI: Agendas 1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Book inventory 1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- By-laws 1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Financial statements 1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- FLAMI: Minutes 1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Membership AMI-NYS & NAMI 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Membership dues 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- FLAMI Program notices 1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Educational conferences & AMI meetings 1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Legislative issues 1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- FLAMI/NAMI: Family Training notebook 1991 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Save Willard P. C. information 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 1992 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- FLAMI newsletter "FLAMI Flyer" 1992 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- FLAMI Membership information 1992 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- FLAMI Program notices 1992 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- NAMI 1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- FLAMI: Agendas 1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- FLAMI: Minutes 1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Financial statements 1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Tompkins Community Hospital Psych Unit 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- MIAW (Mental Illness Awareness Week) 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Book inventory 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Financial statements 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- NAMI Policy Notebook 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Supportive Family Training Syllabus, Sheila Shulman Le Gacy 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
- Willard Psychiatric Center 1993-2007 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- FLAMI: Membership 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- FLAMI: Minutes 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- FLAMI: Program notices 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Tompkins Community Hospital Psych Unit 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- FLAMI: Book list 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- FLAMI: Book inventory 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- NYS Commission on Quality of Care for the Mentally Disabled 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- FLAMI: Financial statements 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- FLAMI: Membership 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- FLAMI: Receipts 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- FLAMI: Financial statements 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- FLAMI: Agendas 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- FLAMI: Minutes 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- FLAMI: Program notices 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- FLAMI: Book inventory 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- FLAMI: 10th Anniversary 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Mental Illness Awareness Week 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Crisis hostel 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- "Times Change: A Collection of Workshop Poetry" 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Supportive Family Training, Sheila Le Gacy 1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- FLAMI: Membership 1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- FLAMI: Financial statements 1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- FLAMI: Agendas 1996 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- FLAMI: Program notices 1996 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- FLAMI: Legislative issues 1996 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- FLAMI: Membership 1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- FLAMI: Financial statements 1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- FLAMI: Agendas 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- FLAMI: Program notices 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- NAMI-NYS/NAMI Name change 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Clipping re State selling closed institutions 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- FLAMI: Membership 1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- FLAMI: Financial statements 1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- FLAMI: Agendas 1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- FLAMI: Program notices 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- NAMI-NYS/NAMI Name change 1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 1999 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- FLAMI: Membership 1999 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- FLAMI: Financial statements & receipts 1999 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- FLAMI: Books purchased 1999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- NAMI-NYS 1999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- NYS Mental Health Documentation Project 1999 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 2000 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- FLAMI: Financial statements 2000 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- FLAMI: Membership 2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- FLAMI: Minutes 2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- FLAMI: Program notices 2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- NAMI-NYS 2000 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- NAMI-NYS: Newsletters 2000 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- NAMI-NYS: Conference materials 2000 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Mental Illmess Awareness Week 2000 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- FLAMI: Correspondence 2001 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- FLAMI: Membership 2001 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- FLAMI: Financial statements 2001 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- FLAMI: Legislative priorities 2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- NAMI-NYS 2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Social Security earnings information 2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Sibling Project 2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- NAMI Conference 2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Calendar 2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- FLAMI/NAMI-FL: Correspondence 2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- FLAMI/NAMI-FL: Membership 2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- FLAMI/NAMI-FL: Receipts 2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- FLAMI/NAMI-FL: Financial statements 2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- NAMI-FL: Agenda 2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- NAMI-FL: Proclamation 2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- NAMI-FL: Affiliate Toolkit 2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- NAMI-FL: Affiliate materials 2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- NAMI-FL: Legislative priorities 2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- NAMI-FL: Supported employment 2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- NAMI-FL: Calendar 2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- FLAMI-NAMI-FL: Correspondence 2003 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- FLAMI-NAMI-FL: Membership 2003 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- NAMI-FL: Receipts 2003 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- NAMI-FL: Financial statements 2003 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- NAMI-NYS: Affiliates Day 2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- NAMI: General information 2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- NAMI-NYS: Family Support and Education Programs 2003 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- NAMI-NYS: Conference 2003 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Mental Illness Awareness Week 2003 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Lenzenwager curriculum vita 2003 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Article re research on mental illness 2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Estate planning outline 2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Calendar 2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- NAMI-FL: Membership 2004 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- NAMI-FL: Financial statements 2004 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- NAMI-FL: Agendas 2004 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- NAMI-NYS 2004 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- NAMI-NYS & FL: Election 2004 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- NAMI-NYS & FL: Educational materials 2004 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Legislative issues 2004 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Mental Illness Awareness Week 2004 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Articles & clippings 2004 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Calendar 2004 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- NAMI-FL: Correspondence 2005 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- NAMI-FL: Receipts 2005 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- NAMI-FL: Financial statements 2005 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- NAMI-FL: Agendas 2005 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- NAMI-FL: Publicity notices 2005 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- NAMI-FL: Programs 2005 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- NAMI-FL: Activities 2005 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- NAMI-FL: Newsletters 2005 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- FLAMI-FL: Website guide 2005 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- NAMI-NYS 2005 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- NAMI 2005 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Obituary 2005 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Miscellany 2005 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Calendar 2005 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- NAMI-FL: Correspondence 2006 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- NAMI-FL: Membership 2006 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- NAMI-FL: Expenses 2006 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- NAMI-FL: Agendas 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- NAMI-FL: Publicity notices 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- NAMI-FL: NAMI-FL News 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- NAMI-FL: Clippings 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- NAMI-FL: Brochures 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- NAMI-FL: Legislative priorities 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- NAMI-FL: Calendar 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- NAMI-FL: Incorporation 2006 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- NAMI-FL: Annual Meeting Reports 2006 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Grading the States 2006 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- NAMI-FL: Correspondence 2007 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- NAMI-FL: Membership 2007 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- NAMI-FL: Agendas 2007 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- NAMI-FL: Publicity notices 2007 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- NAMI-FL: Presentation 2007 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- NAMI-FL: Financial report 2007 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- NAMI-FL: Board Minutes 2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- NAMI-FL: Family to Family classes 2007 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- NAMI: Veterans Resource Center 2007 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- NAMI: information 2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Calendar 2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- NAMI-NYS: Conference 2007 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- NYS Office of Mental Health information 2007 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- NAMI-FL: Membership 2008 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- NAMI-FL: Finances 2008 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- NAMI-FL: Publicity notices 2008 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- NAMI-FL: Programs 2008 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- NAMI-FL: Newsletters 2008 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- NAMI-FL: Calendars 2008 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- NAMI-NYS: Conference 2008 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- NAMI-FL: Correspondence 2009 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- NAMI-FL: Membership 2009 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- NAMI-FL: Finances 2009 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- NAMI-FL: Books 2009 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- NAMI-FL: Publicity notices 2009 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- NAMI-FL: Programs 2009 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- NAMI-FL: Newsletters 2009 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- NAMI 2009 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- NAMI-NYS 2009 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Tompkins County Community Mental Health Services Board 2009 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Calendars 2009 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- NAMI-FL: Correspondence 2010 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- NAMI-FL: Membership 2010 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- NAMI-FL: Financial report 2010 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- NAMI-FL: Program notices 2010 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- NAMI-FL: Articles/clippings 2010 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- NAMI-FL: Booklets 2010 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- NAMI-NYS: Agenda 2010 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- NAMI-NYS: Minutes 2010 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- NAMI-NYS: Articles 2010 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- NAMI-FL: newsletter 2010 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- NYS Government budget 2010 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- NYSEG energy: checklist 2010 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Eligibility for assistance guidelines 2010 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Articles/information 2010 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Community Medical Center Support 2010 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- TC Action 2010 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- TC Mental Health Services 2010 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Calendar 2010 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Audiocassette: Agnes Hatfield, Ph.D., 3rd Annual Educational Conference, tr8786a 1985 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Dr. William Knoedler, 3rd Annual Educational Conference, tr8787a 1985 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Dr. E. Fuller Torrey, 3rd Annual Educational Conference, tr8788a 1985 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Dr. Nancy Andreason presentation, AMI Conference, tr8789a undated (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Dr. Schultz presentation, AMI Conference, tr8790a undated (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Jean Walters, Mental Illness Awareness Week, WHCU, tr8791a 1986 (Box 4)
- Audiocassettes: Update on Schizophrenia, tr8792a-tr8793a 1986 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Herbert Pardes, M.D., Progress in Schizophrenia Research, Schizophrenia Conference, tr8794a 1987 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Francine Cournos, M.D.; Treatment Compliance and Refusal, Progress in Schizophrenia Research, Schizophrenia Conference, tr8795a 1987 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Charles A. Kaufmann, M.D.; Biological Studies in Schizophrenia, Progress in Schizophrenia Research, Schizophrenia Conference, tr8796a 1987 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: E. Fuller Torrey, M.D.; NAMI 1988 annual convention, tr8797a 1988 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Herbert Pardes, M.D., Welcome; Martin S. Willick, M.D., Introduction; Andrew Skodol, M.D.; Loong-Term Follow-Up Studies of Chronic Schizophrenia; Schizophrenia Conference Beyond the Hospital; tr8798a 1988 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Candace Beardsley, M.S.S.W., Kent Smith & Michael H. Wells; Panel - Therapeutic Communities; Schizophrenia Conference Beyond the Hospital; tr8799a 1988 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: William Barry, M.S.W., Harvey Lieberman, Ph.D., & William R. McFarlane, M.D.; Panel - Community Residences; Schizophrenia Conference Beyond the Hospital; tr8800a 1988 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Surviving -- A Wellness Guide, tr8801a 1989 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Esso Leete, NEOAMI Reception, tr8802a 1989 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Manic Depression/Voices of an Illness, narrated by Patty Duke, tr8803a 1992 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: R. Purdy / F. Goodwin, M.D., New Research in Depression & Manic Depression, tr8804a 1994 (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Introduction and Welcome / An Overview of the Biology of Schizophrenia, Recent Advances in Schizophrenia Research, undated (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: New Research on Family Coping Methods, Recent Advances in Schizophrenia Research, tr8806a undated (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Dr. Anthony presentation, AMI Conference, tr8807a undated (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Dr. Meltzer, Opening (A); Dr. Reich, Genetic & Risk Effective Disorder (B), tr8808a undated (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Dr. Reich continued (A), Dr. J. Fawcett, Suicide Factors (B), tr8809a undated (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Dr. Fawcett continued (A), Dr. Schatzberg (A & B), tr8810a undated (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Dr. Schatzberg continued (summary?)(A), Dr. Goodwin (B), tr8811a undated (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Dr. Goodwin continued (A), Seminar: Dr. Reich Genetic DNA, tr8812a undated (Box 4)
- Audiocassette: Recent Advances in Drug Treatment, Recent Advances in Schizophrenia Research, tr8813a undated (Box 4)
- LifeSPAN Toolkit CD: SPAN / An OMH Wellness Iniative (NYS Office of Mental Health) CD-989 2007 (Box 4)
- FLAMI address rubber stamp (Box 4)
- FLAMI bank deposit rubber stamp (Box 4)